## Curriculum Vitae of MD. MEHEDI HASAN



### Career Objective:

I am a progressive professional worker in the development sector with over 3 years of proven experience scholarly engaged with various projects in several organizations. In addition, I am holding a master's degree in Social Science with special concentration on Project Cycle Management, Public Policy Analysis, and Research Methodology. I am currently seeking project management related jobs that will allow me to take challenges and apply my analytical, technical, capacity building, team building, and communications skills.

## Education:

2012-2013 : Master of Social Sciences (M.S.S.), Public Administration, University of Dhaka. 2008-2012 : Bachelor of Social Sciences (B.S.S.), Public Administration, University of Dhaka.

### Professional Experiences:

## February 01, 2018 to Present

Position held : Officer (Project Support)

Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project **Major Projects** 

> Dhaka - CTG - Cox's Bazaar Railway Project Dhaka - Joydevpur - Ishwardy Railway Project

Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

Organization : Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd.

To manage administrative, development, planning, and implementation policies,

procedures and programs in support of the project;

Expedite project implementation by maintaining liaison with government/nongovernment authority, local & international agencies and other stakeholders;

Succinct responsibilities

Review and check documents related with bid, contract and any other request received from project implementing agencies;

Support to prepare presentation, event report, organizing meeting/seminar, internal events, programs & field visit as and when necessary;

Perform any other duties as may be assigned by the authority.

### January 01, 2017 to January 31, 2018

Position held : Field Investigator

**Major Projects** Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project

Third Urban Governance & Infrastructure Improvement Project (UGIIP-3)

Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

Drainage Master Plan Project (16 Districts)

Organization : Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd.

Collaborating with customers, claimants, policyholders & the local administration;

Field visit as and when necessary;

Organize and facilitate focus group discussion;

Support in conducting EMP, social/baseline surveys as and when required; Succinct responsibilities

> Assist in data collection, report preparation and further tasks as per instruction by the authorized management;

Draft accurate and concise reports & presentations based on all collected findings.

### March 01, 2016 to September 30, 2016

Position held : Research Associate

Organization : Human Development Research Centre (HDRC)

#### Distinctive Attributes:

- Profound knowledge on MS Word, MS Excel, PowerPoint, Web Applications, Social Media, HTML, CSS, Oracle/My SQL, Java etc.
- Typing Bangla with Bijoy software
- Flexible to travel frequently
- Team Building Skills

- Ability to work under heavy pressure
- Enthusiastic to explore new places & cultures
- Adaptability with changes
- Well-disciplined & Punctual
- Goal Oriented Skills

## Other Experiences & Voluntary Activities:

- Worked as a Research Associate (Part Time) of Center for Asia-Pacific Initiative (CAPI) for the period of 05.04.2019 to 05.08.2019 on the **Piloting Phase** of SME base Comparative Study in Developing Country
- Worked as a Coordinator in the Social Action Project "ইচ্ছেপ্রণ (Icchepuron)" under the Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training program of British Council, supported by Democracywatch. http://www.dwatchbd.org/ylp1.html
- Conduct several field researches on Contemporary Local Government in Bangladesh, Politicization of Professionals, Migration Pattern in Dhaka city, and Corruption & Tadbir in Bureaucracy.
- Involved in organizing the festival entitled, "Bijoy-e Parbon-e" arranged by Utshe, marking 41st Victory Day of Bangladesh. http://www.thedailystar.net/news-detail-261174
- Founder member of the voluntary group "Friends Society of Rangpur" http://fsrbd.org/
- Voluntary regular **Blood Donor** (26<sup>th</sup> times till now).

# Training and Workshop:

- Trainee (completed) of "IDB-BISEW IT Scholarship Project, Round-39" in "Enterprise Systems Analysis & Design-J2EE". http://idb-bisew.org/
- Participant of the Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training Programme of British Council, supported by Democracywatch. <a href="https://www.britishcouncil.org/active-citizens">https://www.britishcouncil.org/active-citizens</a>
- Attended the Climate Culture and Art Symposium 2018 for Youth in Bangladesh under the Gobeshona Young Researcher's programme organized by ICCCAD. http://art-symposium-4youth.icccad.net/
- A Six (6) months training experience on Social Compliance and CSR Issues, organized by Institute of Apparel Research and Technology, (BKMEA). <a href="http://www.bkmea.com/training\_institite.html">http://www.bkmea.com/training\_institite.html</a>

### Personal Information:

Address : Central Road First Drive, House – 111, Flat – 5B, Kolabagan, Dhaka-1205.

: +880-1717-677451, +880-1918-629865 Contact No

: mhshuvo29@gmail.com E-mail : Bangladeshi by Birth **Nationality** 

Languages : Advanced Bangla, Fluent English and some understanding of Hindi.

Passport No : BM0481157 Blood group : O Positive

### Distinction:

: Got a board scholarship for achieving Golden A<sup>+</sup>.

### References:

Abu Jubayer, Director (Operation), Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd. and Deputy Referee 1

Director (Operation), CCECR, Stamford University Bangladesh, Dhaka.

Cell: +880-1711459532 Email: jubayer.buet.bd@gmail.com

Md. Mehedi Hasan, Assistant Judge, District & Sessions Judge Court, Rangpur. Referee 2

Cell: +880-1710-491199 Email: mmhasan508@gmail.com

## Acknowledgement:

I, the undersigned hereby certify that, to the best of my knowledge and belief, above mentioned credentials correctly describe myself, and I will be liable for any feigned information.

Md. Mehedi Hasan nebolihosan